Colin Shea

DEV & OPS EXPERT

colin@shea.at http://evaryont.me/ (301)-337-7181 Phoenix, AZ USA

Profile

Throughly research ideas and solutions before implementations. Leave room for changes in the future; things will not go as planned.

Skills

System Administration Web Development

Effectively administers core and ancillary systems. Proactively identifies and troubleshoots problems.

Build great tools and websites, whether internal or public. Modular architecture for later changes and improvements.

Network Security

Create policies that withstand and quickly recover from network attacks. Stay abreast of the state of the art in security.

Technical

HTML	Chef	Ubuntu	Python	KVM
Ruby	Puppet	Debian	Java	AWS
git	Ansible	CentOS	XMPP/Jabber	VMware

Experiences

The Evogi Group - http://www.evogi.com/

September 2013 - June 2015

System Administrator

Managing the fleet of 1,000+ servers in AWS while upgrading from legacy Chef 11 and shell scripts to Chef 12. Designing and developing security software to audit users connecting to the network.

Cummings Engineering Consultants Linux Geek

January 2012 - April 2013

Expanding the configuration management tools to cover previously manual processes. Developing modules for puppet for NSA security guidelines.

<u>University of Advancing Technology -</u> <u>https://www.uat.edu/</u>

August 2011 - December 2011

Intern

Helped out with networking and Linux related tasks in the IT department.

[Buffer]Overflow - http://root-the-box.com/

January 2011 - October 2011

Chairman of the Root The Box Committee

As a chairman, it was my responsibility to help the [Buffer]Overflow Officer managing the entire committee in any way. Primarily, it was outside communication with the head chiefs of each division. There were weekly status reports, but that was not enough, especially in the couple of weeks before the event. Also, if the officer did not show up to a meeting, the chairman assumes his responsibility until the officer returns.

Econify - http://www.econify.com/

June 2010 - August 2010

Programming Intern

Develop new features clients requested as well as help structure and plan out new projects for the company

<u>Montgomery County Students Information</u> <u>Technology Foundation - http://itfcareers.org/</u>

September 2008 - May 2010

Computer repair technician

Projects

cattle-ranch - https://github.com/evaryont/cattle-ranch

15 June 2014 - Present

Wrapper cookbooks and recipes to automate building & managing my network

mousehole - https://github.com/evaryont/mousehole

2 September 2005 - 28 August 2009

An HTTP proxy written in Ruby to allow users to change the web to their preferences

arson - https://github.com/evaryont/cattle-ranch

4 April 2008 - 12 August 2009

A download-only tool to help Arch users install packages from the AUR

Education

University of Advancing Technology - http://uat.edu, Tempe, Arizona USA

2010 - 2013

Triple Major, Open Source Technologies, Network Security & Network Engineering

Links

Website - http://evaryont.me

Code - https://github.com/evaryont

Twitter -

https://twitter.com/evaryont

Colin Shea — colin@shea.at — (301)-337-7181 Also on LinkedIn.